E. P. Dutton & Company, Inc. Records
E. P. Dutton & Company, Inc. Records
- Children's editor's files
  - Wheeler - Wolff (Box 79)
    Wolff and Owett Let's Imagine Being Places
    Wolff and Owett Let's Imagine Sounds
  - Wolff - Wymer (Box 79)
    Wolff amd Owett Let's Imagine Thinking Things
    Woodward, Helen Fun Foods and Fixings
    Woody, Regina Dancing For Joy
    Wymer, Norman Gilbert and Sullivan
  - Yates, Elizabeth (Box 79)
    Yates, Elizabeth/MacDonald Sir Gibbie Pub. 8/30/65
    Yates, Elizabeth Pebble in a Pool (D.C.F.)
  - Yates - Young Traveler (Box 79)
    Yates, Elizabeth Someday You'll Write
    "The Young Traveler In Greece" Trease, Geoffrey
    "The Young Traveler In India and Pakistan" Trease, Geoffrey
    "The Young Traveler In Portugal" Wyatt, Honor
    "The Young Traveler In West Indies" Iremonger, Lucille
  - Zappler - Zemach (Box 79)
    Zappler, George (Nature Book) Correspondence
    Zarem, Lewis The Green Man From Space
    Zarem, Lewis New Dimensions of Flight
    Zarem, Lewis New Era of Flight
    Zarem, Lewis Superjet
    Zemach, Margot & Harre A Hat With A Rose
  - Addresses - American Library Association (Box 79)
    Addresses (Addresses of Authors & Artists for Spring 1962-1963 Juvenile Books)
    AIGA Correspondence
    The American Jewish Community Correspondence
    ALA Convention 1961
    ALA Convention 1962
    ALA Convention 1962 Report for Children's Book Council
    ALA Convention 1963 Report in Convention
    ALA Convention 1963
  - Asia - Ask To See (correspondence) (Box 79)
    Asia Society Booklet "Books on Asia for Children")
    "Ask To See" Manuscripts 1961
    "Ask To See" Manuscripts 1962
    "Ask To See" Manuscripts 1963
  - Banigan - Bradley (correspondence) (Box 79)
    Sharon Bannigan
    Barrie & Rockliff, Eng. pub. gen.
    Berna, Paul Cheral Sans Tete
    Blackie & Sons, Ltd., Eng., Pub., Gen
    Book Fairs 1960 programs
    Book Fairs 1962-1963
    Bradley, Duane Cappy, the Jet-Propelled Boy
  - Brand - CBC (Box 79)
    Brand, Oscar Old Bangum
    "Carnival of Books" 1958-1960
    Caroline Series
    Chappell, Richard
    Child Study Association
    CBC
  - Children's Book Council (correspondence) - Dutton Macrae Award (Box 79)
    CBC 1962
    Christopher Award
    Christy & Moon, Ltd. Eng. Pub. General
    Cross, Joe A.
    Current Award File
    Dent-Bozman, Green, Dent
    Diggot, Juliet Curtis Brown, Ltd.
    Dutton-Macrae Award
  - Evarts - Letterworth Press (Box 79)
    Everts, Hal
    Exibits
    Foreign Publishers, Misc.
    George, Mabel E. Oxford University Press
    Goldin, Augusta R.
    Hogarth, Grace (constable & company Ltd. Eng.)
    Hope Leresche & Steele, Eng. Agent General
    Horn Book
    Jones, Olive General Methuer
    Juvenile Ads
    Letterworth Press, Eng. Pub. Gen.
  - McLaughlin - Macrae, Elliot (Box 79)
    McLaughlin, Tom - Workshop for Librarians
    Macrae, Elliot
    EMB European Trip 1963 Elliot Macrae's Reports
  - Macrae, Elliot - References (Box 79)
    EMB Mongolian Trip 1962 Itinerary & report
    Mathamatics Magazine April 1962
    O'Dea, Catherine T. Correspondence
    Office Supplies - book order forms
    Organizations, Misc. Requests, information corres. fliers
    Phoenix House, Eng. Pub. Gen.
    Radio & Television Misc.
    Record Projects
    References
  - Rejections I - A (misc.), B (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections II - B, 1957-1962 (Box 80)
  - Rejections III - C (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections IV - D (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections V - E (misc.), F (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections VI - G (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections VII - H (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections VIII - M (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Rejections IX - S (misc.) (Box 80)
  - Routledge - Wonderful World of Electronics (Box 80)
    Routledge, Kegan Paul Eng. Pub. Gen.
    Schools
    Taylor, Judy (Bodley Head)
    Thomas Moore Association
    Tintin Books - Herge
    Tworkov/Duvoisin Picture Parade of Books The Camel Who Took A Walk
    Writer's Digest
    The Wonderful World of Electronics Ashmead, Gordon)
- Photographs
  - Portrait (painted) of E.P. Dutton, 5 copies (Oversize 1)
  - Portrait of E.P. Dutton by Pach Brothers, 2 copies (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs of E.P. Dutton (folder), 3 photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Portrait (painted) of E.P. Dutton, 1919 (Oversize 1)
  - Photograph of Mr. and Mrs. Dutton taken around 1860 (envelope), with engraving of the Antique Building in Boston (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs of interior and exterior of E.P. Dutton Bookstore (envelope), 7 photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs from the New York Times Book Review of Dutton authors Vladimir Dudintsev, A.A. Milne, and Van Wyck Brooks (envelope) (Oversize 1)
  - Portrait (reproduction) of E. P. Dutton, 16 copies (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs (folder) (includes photograph of Dutton authors John Vassos, Helen Welshimer) (Oversize 1)
  - Folders of photographs from Pach Brothers, some signed, some with letters to the firm, including many notable names such as J.P. Morgan, Henry Gassaman Davis, William McAdoo, John Milton Hay. (Oversize 1)
  - Photograph of E.P. Dutton holding open book, 4 copies (Oversize 18)
- News clippings
  - Carlson, John Ray, scrapbook sheets (not bound) (Oversize 2)
  - Sagan, Francoise, loose clippings (Oversize 2)
    Authors: Sagan (clippings, correspondence, and a story manuscript, Boxes 11 and 12),
    Production files: book reviews (review of Those Without Shadows, Box 28)
  - Sagan, Françoise, news clippings; 1 volume; See also: Authors: Sagan (clippings, correspondence, and a story manuscript, Boxes 11 and 12), Production files: book reviews (review of Those Without Shadows, Box 28) (Oversize 2)
  - Newspaper Advertisements, 1 volume (Oversize 3)
  - Magazine Advertisements, 1 volume (Oversize 4)
  - Advertisements, 2 volumes (Oversize 4-5)
  - Information on Authors and Books (Oversize 6)
  - Publicity Department Releases, 1924-1927 (Oversize 6)
  - News of Books and Authors (Oversize 7)
- Letter books
  - Country Life Stories, 1 volume; pages of an 1857 Boston newspaper inside volume (Oversize 7)
  - John Macrae: Tribute — Fifteenth Year in Advertising, 1935; 1 volume (Oversize 7)
  - Acknowledgements, 1 volume (Oversize 8)
- Manufacturing books
  See also Financial: Manufacturing Book 1901-1906 (Box 15)
  - Domestic, 1904-1919; 1 volume (Oversize 9)
  - Domestic, 1919-1923; 1 volume (Oversize 10)
- Importation books
  - Foreign, 1905-1925; 1 volume (Oversize 11)
  - Dent Importations, 1910-1926; 1 volume (Oversize 12)
- Miscellaneous
  - Everyman's Library
    - 1906-1936, 1 volume (Oversize 13)
    - 1915-1936, 1 volume (Oversize 14)
    - Ernest Nister, 1912-1925; 1 volume (Oversize 18)
    - George Routledge and Sons, 1912-1925; 1 volume (Oversize 19)
  - Award - United States Department of Commerce, 1957 (Oversize 17)